《指定幸存者》前情提要
Previously on "Designated Survivor"...
是杀死马吉德·纳萨尔的凶手
It's the man who killed Majid Nassar.
我认为幕后凶手
I think the people who did this
正强迫杰森做一些事情
are trying to make Jason do something.
给你一小时
You have an hour.
在那之后  你儿子要么能安全回家
After that, you'll either find your son safe at home...
要么不能
or not.
是我杀了马吉德·纳萨尔
I killed Majid Nassar.
联调局的副局长
The deputy director of the FBI
杀死了世界上的头号恐怖分子吗
killed the world's most wanted terrorist?
恐怕是这样的
I'm afraid so.
开心点  彼得
Cheer up, Peter.
你只有一步之遥了
You're about to be a heartbeat away.
假设你当了副总统
Assuming you make it to V.P.,
当我扳倒他时
When I take Kirkman down,
我保证我也不会放过你的
I'll make sure I don't leave you behind.
晚上11点14分
11:14 p.m.
-去查  -等等
- Look into it. - Wait.
正在传送
正在传送  100%
国安局
指定幸存者
第一季 第九集
翻译： sienna  Silence  panglovelai  长颈鹿  青椒
■
尊敬的议长女士  恭喜您高升
Madam Speaker, congratulations on your new position.
让我先问您
Let me start by asking,
翻译：尤妮希  桃子  持久  天青月白  星星与野狗
您是否也像您议会的同事一样
do you, like your colleagues in the Senate,
认为这些听证会
view these confirmation hearings
只是走走形式呢
as anything more than a formality?
翻译：murky  薇薇安      校对：小早   克里斯
汤姆·柯特曼成为我们的总统
Tom Kirkman is our President
只是因为他不在国情咨文的现场
because he wasn't - at the State of the Union.
彼得·麦克利什爆炸里活着  就成了英雄
Peter MacLeish is a hero because he lived through it.
时间轴：   Avis   壬虚浪影
然而  要领导一个国家
Certainly, survival shouldn't be the only qualification
金布尔·霍斯拉滕议长讨论彼得·麦克利什
后期：虫虫不咬人    总监：小早
幸存不是唯一的资格  对吧
when it comes to leading our country, should it?
你威胁到她了
She's intimidated by you.
她已经在各大台说了一轮了
She's done everything from "Megyn Kelly" to "Jimmy Kimmel."
这可不只是"威胁"
"Intimidated" isn't the word that comes to mind.
新议会中有162位独立人士
162 Independents in the new house.
她除了认可你为
How can she read that
美国第一位独立人士票选总统以外
as anything other than America's endorsement
别无他法
of their first Independent President?
相信我  她能找到方法的
Trust me. She'll find a way.
议长女士  你希望我们能从
Madam Speaker, - what do you hope to learn
金布尔·霍斯拉滕议长讨论彼得·麦克利什
麦克利什议员的证词了解到什么呢
from Congressman MacLeish's testimony?
她对我们的候选人
Has she done any irrevocable damage
造成什么不可挽回的伤害了没
to our nominee this morning?
没有  只是继续无休止地
No, just continuing her never-ending quest
质疑他的提名资格
to cast doubt on his qualifications.
她没有暗示参议院资格就算好的了
She'd be better off taking a cue from the Senate.
他们清楚地表明
They made it perfectly clear.
谁也不想留下玩弄阴谋诡计的证据
No one wants to play politics with this confirmation.
我真希望在全民
I wish I saw her face
一致投票支持后  看看她的表情
when the vote came back unanimous.
你觉得她会气得耳朵冒烟吗
You think steam can actually come out of someone's ears?
你记得我的要求吧
You remembered my order.
双份浓缩黑咖啡
Double Americano.
三份香草  一份焦糖
Three pumps vanilla, one pump caramel.
太搞笑了  不会忘的
It's too ridiculous to forget.
你们怎么这么淡定  你们没看邮件吗
Why are you guys so calm? Don't you check your e-mail?
才45秒钟没看  怎么了
Not in the last 45 seconds. Why?
发生安全漏洞
A security breach.
好  跟国安局局长联系
All right, let's get the NSA director on the phone.
在通知总统之前  搞清事情始末
I want the full story before we notify the President.
开工
Let's go.
他们整个上午都在翻亚特伍德的办公室
They've been digging through Atwood's office all morning.
-你知道怎么回事吗  -内部检查
- You know what's going on? - It's an internal review.
亚特伍德为什么会被内部调查
Why is Atwood being investigated?
你怎么知道发生了什么事
How do you know that's what's happening?
因为内部调查的老大走过来了
Because here comes the Director of Internal Affairs
约翰·法索
John Foerstel.
你好  威尔士探员
Agent Wells. Hi.
借一步说话
A word?
他的名字是加百利·汤普森
His name is Gabriel Thompson.
过去二十年来
He worked as a systems analyst
他一直担任国家安全局的系统分析员
for the National Security Agency for the last 20 years.
国安局
机密
他昨天就这样带着大批机密资料
And yesterday he just walked out the front door
走出国安局大门吗
with a ton of classified information?
今早  国安局宣布这是一起
Which this morning the NSA is calling
-极度严重的信息泄露  -有多严重
- a "Significant breach." - How significant?
汤普森拿走的硬盘原型机
Well, the prototype hard drive Thompson took
能够保存万亿字节的文件
is capable of storing terabytes of files.
国安局估计需要耗费多日
NSA estimates it'll take days
才能梳理系统  评估失窃数据情况
to comb through the system and assess the stolen data.
幸运的话  别让媒体听到风声
Luckily, the press hasn't gotten wind of that.
他们早晚会知道的
Well, only a matter of time before that happens.
同意  我们对这个汤普森的了解有多少
Agreed. What do we know about this Thompson?
这是间谍活动吗
I mean, is this espionage?
有外国政府牵涉在内吗
Is a foreign government involved?
这点不确定  长官
Well, it's uncertain, sir.
国安局正在倾尽全力追查他的下落
NSA's throwing all their resources into tracking him down.
惠特克保证  一旦他获悉更多情况
And Whitaker promised to brief you
会立即向你汇报
as soon as he knows more.
这件事我们必须抢占先机
We need to get ahead of this now.
很高兴见到你  威尔士探员
It's nice to see you, Agent Wells.
很久不见了
It's been a while.
约翰  你是内务部的
Well, John, in your line of work,
通常来说  见不到你反而是件好事
that's generally considered a good thing.
我知道你和杰森·亚特伍德关系要好
Look, I know that you were close with Jason Atwood,
但是这份友情也许会给你带来麻烦
but it's a friendship that could cause problems for you.
为什么
Why?
-也要调查我吗  -拜托
- Am I under investigation, too? - Come on.
你很聪明  应该知道你必然牵扯其中
You're smart enough to know that you're wrapped up in this.
纳萨尔被谋杀时  你和杰森都在监狱里
You were with Jason at the prison when Nassar was murdered.
审讯期间  你也和他一起
You were there with him during the interrogation.
这次调查的意义何在
What is the point of this?
你应该很清楚杰森不是谋杀犯
You of all people know that Jason's not a murderer.
我也不能忽视他的供词
Well, I can't exactly ignore a confession.
如果这是预料之事
If this was so cut-and-dry,
你何必还要调查呢
why are you doing an investigation at all?
好吧  这理由我接受
All right, I'll bite.
如果杰森·亚特伍德没杀马吉德·纳萨尔
If Jason Atwood didn't kill Majid Nassar,
那是谁杀的
who did?
你现在的处境并没好到哪去  汉娜
You're not doing yourself any favors, Hannah.
我知道比起联邦检察官的查问
And I know you'd rather answer my questions
你更愿意回答我的问题
than a federal prosecutor's.
-我们曾经立场一致  -是的
- We used to be on the same side. - Yeah.
如果你和杰森学会如何照章办事
And we still would be
正如我多年前警告过你们的那样
if you and Jason had ever learned how to play by the rules
我们的立场仍然是一致的
like I warned you to years ago.
而不是像现在这样
Instead, here we are.
还有  汉娜
Oh, and, Hannah,
今天下午  我会去看杰森
I'm paying Jason a visit this afternoon.
你的说词最好不要有出入
Your stories better match.
喂
Hello?
恰克  你能否把彼得·麦克利什的审核资料
Hey, Chuck, think you can get the Peter MacLeish
从资源管理情报系统中调出来
vetting files out of the RMD
-二十分钟后在我家见面  -好
- and meet me at my house in 20 minutes? - Yes.
但是汉娜  到底发生了什么事
But, Hannah, what the hell's going on?
到了那我再向你解释
I'll explain when you get there.
你给艾米丽买了咖啡  从来没有我的份
You brought Emily coffee? You never bring me coffee.
-你找我干嘛  赛斯  -马吉德·纳萨尔
- What do you want, Seth? - Majid Nassar.
他没复活吧
He's still dead, right?
还记不记得我和你说过
Remember when I told you
媒体可能很想知道是谁杀了
the press was gonna want answers on who killed
-美国史上头号恐怖分子  -记得
- the most-wanted terrorist in U.S. history? - Yeah.
事实确实如此  非常迫切
Well, I'm telling you they want answers.
你得拖住他们  赛斯
Well, you got to hold them off, Seth.
我什么时候才不用呢
And when I can't?
是等《华盛顿邮报》开专栏呢
When the Post runs an op-ed
还是等《泰晤士报》指责我们掩盖事实呢
or when the Times accuses us of a cover-up?
总统今天要和联调局的人会面
Listen, POTUS is meeting with the FBI today.
争取点时间  让我们找出答案
Just buy us some time to get the answers we need.
如果你帮忙  下次我给你买咖啡
And if you do, then coffee for you next time.
好吧
All right.
来看看这个
Hey, look at this.
加百利·汤普森
Gabriel Thompson just dumped
刚刚在维基解密上放出了大量政府文件
a massive amount of government documents on WikiLeaks.
不是吧  维基解密吗
Seriously? WikiLeaks?
这不是揭发者的老把戏吗
Isn't that, like, a whistleblower cliché?
但这些文件与前政府官员
Not when the docs are all linked
联系起来的时候就不再是谣言了
to members of - the previous administration.
柯克曼也曾在前政府任职
Which Kirkman served in.
维基解密网上持续爆出
Material continues to be released via WikiLeaks
国家安全局资料泄露
国安局揭发者声称里士满政府内阁贪污腐败
里士满政府内阁成员
involving questionable activities
不法行为的证据
by members of President Richmond's cabinet.
证据显示某些内阁成员
It appears that several cabinet members
曾滥用职权收受贿赂
were abusing their power
大开方便之门
by receiving money in exchange for access.
他声称里士满政府内阁贪污腐败
Okay, so he's claiming that Richmond's cabinet was corrupt.
我想我们可以排除他是间谍的嫌疑
I guess we can take espionage off the list.
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
超乎想象  总统先生
It looks a lot worse than it is, sir.
是的  大概就是付费玩家模式
Yeah, pay-for-play sort of things, mostly.
财政部长拿了钱
The Treasury Secretary was paid to give speeches
去银行家聚会上发表讲话
at corporate retreats for banking CEOs.
商务部长去海外研究的费用
Commerce Secretary - took overseas research trips
由外国游说团体承担
paid for by foreign lobby groups.
看起来很可怕
The optics are terrible,
但并不属于重大犯罪
but it's not exactly high crimes.
但他们的行为的确是犯罪  不是吗
But they are crimes, right?
从法律角度讲是这样的
Counsel's office says yes,
但迄今为止  非议很少
but so far the blow-back's been minimal,
而且他所提及的大部分人
and most of the people that he's referencing
都已经死于国会爆炸案了
died during the Capitol bombing.
只剩我的资料未被公开
Everyone but me.
这也是问题之一  总统先生
And that's a problem, sir.
为什么  他说什么了
Why? What did he say?
正是这样
Well, that's exactly it.
您的档案并未公开
Your files haven't been released.
-他为何隐瞒我的档案  -这也许是个策略
- Why would he hold my files back? - Maybe it's a strategy.
他要等到媒体极度兴奋之时再公开
He's waiting till the press is in a frenzy
这样他就能吸引全国人民的关注
so he has the whole country's attention.
听着  我不想这么问您
Look, I-I hate to ask,
但如果势必会受到攻击
but if we're gonna get hit,
我们必须要知道该如何去回应
we need to know how to respond.
总统先生  您有没有不可告人的秘密
And Mr. President, do you have anything to hide?
我有没有不可告人的秘密
Do I have anything to hide?
很抱歉这么问  总统先生
I'm sorry to ask, Mr. President,
我们只是想保护您
but we just want to protect you.
我很感谢  亚伦
I appreciate that, Aaron.
我没有什么好隐藏的  我没有秘密
No, I have nothing to hide. No secrets.
他会不会知道有关李奥亲生父亲的事
Is it possible that he knows about Leo's paternity question?
那没什么好挖的
It's a non-story.
就像丽萨·乔丹一样  他们迟早会知道的
They'd find that out as quickly as Lisa Jordan did.
也许他知道我们正在审理亚特伍德认罪案件
Maybe he knows we're sitting on the Atwood confession.
我已经被一些媒体追问了
I've been getting hit from some national newspaper guys.
我们没有审理任何案件  我们是在调查
We're not sitting on anything. We're investigating.
一旦查出真凶  我们会立刻通知民众
As soon as we have answers, so will the American people.
为什么这个所谓的揭发者
So why would this so-called whistleblower
将所有内阁成员的纳税申报单和银行记录
release every cabinet member's tax returns,
公之于众
their banking records,
唯独没有您的呢
except yours?
听着  我们可以花一天时间来推测
Look, - we can speculate all day
汤普森先生可能会如何对付我
on what Mr. Thompson thinks he might have on me.
但真正需要做的是找到他
The truth is we need to find him.
在国安局查清楚他到底偷走了什么之前
Until the NSA knows exactly what he's stolen,
他对国家安全都是个威胁
he's a threat - to our national security.
好的  总统先生  我们会密切关注此事
All right, sir, we'll stay on top of it,
-并随时向您报告  -谢谢
- keep you posted. - Thank you.
直说好了
Let me get this straight.
你是说彼得·麦克利什
You're saying that Peter MacLeish,
也就是副总统候选人
the guy about to be confirmed as vice president,
涉嫌策划
is somehow involved in the conspiracy
国会爆炸案
that destroyed the Capitol.
我明白  这让人很难接受
I know. It's a lot to process.
我父母离婚曾给我造成很大的打击
My parents' divorce was a lot to process.
而这个还要更大  汉娜
This is next-level, Hannah.
我不知道  但你把这些东西摆在我面前
I don't know, but it's also hard to ignore
我也无法视而不见
when you lay it all out like this.
有个问题
Here's the problem.
法索已经怀疑我了
Foerstel's already suspicious of me.
但我不能放过麦克利什  至少现在不能
But I can't back off MacLeish. Not now.
我需要能扳倒他的确凿证据
I need hard evidence against him,
但目前我掌握的唯一证据是...
but the only evidence I have right now...
我知道  晚上11点14分
I know. I know. 11:14 p.m.
没错
Right.
我都查遍了  但一无所获
I looked everywhere. I've got nothing.
这就是为什么你要复查麦克利什的档案
Right, which is why you need to re-examine MacLeish's files
看看有没有相关之处
and see if there's a connection.
品牌广告推广合作  普罗米修斯  plmxs2016@gmail.com
恰克  我知道你为了帮我冒着很大风险
Chuck, I know you're taking a risk by being here,
如果你要退出的话  我可以理解
so if you needed to leave, I'd understand.
汉娜  每次你来找我帮忙
Hannah, when you come asking for help,
都不会是易事
it's never easy,
品牌广告推广合作  普罗米修斯  plmxs2016@gmail.com
有时甚至是违法的
and sometimes not even legal.
但你既聪明又敬业  一般不会出错
But you're smart and dedicated and usually right,
所以告诉我需要做什么就好
so tell me what I need to do.
雷伯恩众议院办公楼
说实话  仅因你对总统有意见
To be honest, I'm not comfortable
我是不会去追查
going after the "Miracle on the Potomac"
"联邦政府的生存奇迹"的
just because you've got a bone to pick with the president.
议员  你初来乍到
Congressman, you're new here.
让我来指点你一下
So let me give you a little bit of free advice.
华盛顿特区里全靠关系
D.C. is all about relationships.
你最好不要
And this relationship, yours and mine,
搞僵你我之间的关系
is not one you want to sour.
听证会只是确认  而非加冕
This is a confirmation, not a coronation.
谨应总统所需并非我们的职责所在
It's not our job to give the president what he wants.
为国家着想才是
Our job is to determine what's best for the country.
知道了
Yes, ma'am.
容我失陪一会  里面见
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'll see you inside.
议员  麦克利什夫人
Congressman, Mrs. MacLeish.
金布尔  希望你今天别让他太轻松
Kimble, I hope you're not too easy on him today.
真高兴能遇见你
I'm so glad I ran into you.
没能在开始前祝福你的话
I would have hated starting the day
我会遗憾的
without wishing you the best of luck.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much. I really appreciate that.
议员
Congresswoman.
我能问一下
Do you mind if I ask what it is
你打算如何对付我和柯克曼吗
you have against Kirkman and myself?
我不相信
I don't trust anyone
任何一辈子衣食无忧的人
who has things handed to them in life...
尤其是权利从天而降
Especially power.
晚上11点14分
11:14 p.m.
美军退伍报告
我没看出任何东西  汉娜
I got nothing here, Hannah.
我知道这听起来有点扯
I know it sounds crazy,
但我的线人说中了105室
but my source was right about Room 105.
说中了麦克利什
She was right about MacLeish,
所以这条线索一定有用
so there's got to be something to this.
我原以为能从这些档案的时间戳里
I thought that I would find those numbers
与此相似的时间点
on some of the time stamps on the files.
万一这并不代表时间呢
What if it's not a time?
这可能是个日期
I mean, what if it's a date?
看看这个  这是他在阿富汗执行那次
Look at this. This... This is the after-action report
为他赢得铜星勋章的任务的事后报告
that earned him the Bronze Star in Afghanistan.
2005年11月14号
November 14, 2005.
彼得·麦克利什
美国陆军上尉
11月14号  PM
11/14 PM.
P.M...
-彼得·麦克利什  -彼得·麦克利什
- Peter MacLeish. - Peter MacLeish.
很好
Okay.
但这份文件还不是确凿的证据
Okay, but this document isn't exactly a smoking gun.
麦克利什的部队被塔利班所袭击
MacLeish's unit was attacked by the Taliban,
他想救自己的战友
and he managed to save most of his men.
这份报告只是对他的勇敢与英雄主义的认可
I mean, this report's an endorsement of his bravery and heroism.
没错  但第一次听到105室时
Yes, but Room 105, at a first glance,
你也没想到这会是个防爆掩体  不是吗
didn't look like a bomb shelter, did it?
你觉得他的档案没写明事件的全过程
You think his file isn't telling you the whole story?
我想知道当时在场的人是怎么说的
I think that I'd like to hear from the men who were there,
看看他们是不是也这么认为
whether they saw things the same way.
作为国会爆炸案的唯一幸存者
To be the only survivor of the Capitol bombing,
众议院司法委员会听证会
关于麦克利什议员担任副总统事宜的听证会
并不足以让我仕途亨通
I know, does not qualify me for higher office,
但当柯克曼总统...
but when President Kirkman...
麦克利什说得很精彩
MacLeish is crushing it.
-这家伙很适合上电视  -是啊
- This guy was made for TV. - I know.
如果这样还不能解决的话
If we don't wrap this up today,
我觉得你可以直接讨伐霍斯拉滕蓄意拖延
I think you can go hard after Hookstraten for holding it up.
到时候舆论肯定会向着我们
I mean, public opinion will definitely be in our favor.
维基解密又有新内容了
Another dump on WikiLeaks.
国会议事录  电子邮件  立法汇报会
Congressional memos, e-mails, legislative briefings.
应该没有柯克曼的把柄
Doesn't look like anything on Kirkman.
对  这些东西影响不到他
No, nothing here can touch him.
不对
That's not true.
你们看到有关黑兹尔顿参议员的泄漏记录了吗
Have you seen the leaked memo on Senator Hazelton?
他要是能一直退休  国家会更美好
The country would've been better off if he'd stayed retired.
虽然这是事实  但他的办公室刚打来电话
Well, that might be true, but his office just called.
我们惹到了华盛顿特区
We just pissed off the one man in Washington
最惹不起的人
we can't afford to piss off.
我们怎么惹到他了
How did we piss him off?
黑兹尔顿参议员
Senator Hazelton?
上次任期结束后他本已经退休
He retired at the end of last term.
但是国会爆炸案之后他复任了
He came back after the Capitol bombing
因为佛特蒙州的州长指任了他
when the governor of Vermont appointed him.
而且他还刚被任命为
And just named the new chair
参议院拨款委员会新任主席
of the Senate Appropriations Committee.
这位参议员权倾政界
The senator has tremendous power.
拨款委员会有权拒绝
His committee can lock down
我们提议的任何债务  税收  和开支法案
any debt, tax, spending bill we suggest.
记录里什么内容这么严重
And what about the memo was so offensive?
"黑泽尔顿参议员是个老淫魔"
"Senator Hazelton is a lecherous old man
"只想猥亵女职员"
more accustomed to groping female staff
"而不想重用她们"
than promoting them."
所以这关我什么事
Again, why is this my problem?
因为他要求你立刻解雇作者
Because he wants you to fire the author immediately.
好吧  作者是谁
Okay, who's the author?
是我  先生
I am, sir.
参议员  请您理解
Senator, please understand
我所写的文字
that my words are in no way a reflection
与总统对您的看法毫无关系
of how the president feels about you.
那段话是很多年前写的
That was written years ago,
当时我还不认识总统先生
long before I even met the president.
如果我的所作所为让您难堪  我很抱歉
I sincerely apologize for embarrassing you in any way.
你觉得这就够了吗
And you think that's enough?
参议员  我知道你希望我解雇罗迪斯女士
Senator, I know you want me to fire Ms. Rhodes,
但我已经认识艾米丽很多年了
but I've known Emily for many years.
我可以向你保证  她是诚心道歉的
And I can tell you her apology is sincere.
她是挺诚心的
Oh, she means it all right.
因为她现在害怕了
Now. When she's scared.
她当初污言秽语诽谤我的时候
She had a whole different attitude
态度可不是现在这样
when she first wrote that smear,
那时她就是个无名小卒
back when she was a nobody,
政府里的小啰喽  却狂妄自大
a jumped-up little House staffer,
而我是财政委员会主席  为两任内阁效力
and I was finance chairman, served in two cabinets,
连续六次获选连任
elected to six consecutive terms.
参议员  我明白您的意思
Again, Senator, I hear what you're saying.
我只是希望能找到办法解决此事
I'm just trying to find us a way to move forward.
总统先生  我放弃退休选择复任
Mr. President, I came out of retirement to serve again
是因为国家需要我
because my country needed me.
我刚帮助你提名彼得·麦克利什
I just helped your nominee, Peter MacLeish,
迅速获得了参议院的认可
through a speedy Senate confirmation,
你就这样感谢我吗
and this is my reward?
让你手下的职员肆意中伤我
To be libeled by one of your staffers?
参议员  这些泄漏的文件对我们都很不利
Senator, we were all thrown by these leaked documents.
我们应该追查泄漏原因
I just think we should be going after
查清幕后黑手  而不是讨伐文件作者
the people that leaked them, not the people that wrote them.
不好意思  总统先生
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
如果是你的声名有损
Perhaps you would feel differently
你大概就不会这样想了
if it was your character that had been smeared.
你知道我在参议院有多大权力
You know the power I wield in the Senate.
我给你时间考虑  这件事该怎么解决
I'll give you some time to consider in what way
应该造成多大的影响
and how publicly you want to do this.
但是解决结果必须是她被辞退
But she needs to be gone by the end of business.
-告退  -慢走
- Mr. President. - Senator.
简直不敢相信
Unbelievable.
不管愿不愿意
Like it or not,
我们最好不要与他为敌
he's not an enemy you want to make.
他能推迟你未来三年的
He can hold up your entire economic agenda
整个经济计划
for the next three years.
您别无选择
You don't have a choice.
您必须让我辞职
You have to accept my resignation.
感谢你的提问  我能理解
I appreciate the question, and I -- and I understand it.
我的公众生活一直毫无秘密可言
Um, my public life's been an open book.
我从小就谨记
Ever since I was a little boy,
约翰·F·肯尼迪对于服役的号召
I-I took to heart John F. Kennedy's call to service.
我希望这次听证会
I hope over the course of this hearing,
能让你们看到  我没有辜负这个使命
you're seeing how I lived up to that call.
你认为自己有资格
And do you think you're qualified
众议院司法委员会
确认麦克利什议员出任副总统
出任副总统一职吗
for the office of Vice President?
我父亲从小就教我
My father instilled in me
-没有比这更崇高的使命了  -你看他
- that there is no higher calling... - Look at him.
一副要当开国元勋的样子
It's like - he's channeling Camelot.
长得也有点像肯尼迪家的
He even looks like a Kennedy.
这是11月14日任务中
Here's the contact info
麦克利什那八位队员的联系方式
for the eight members of MacLeish's unit on the 11/14 mission
他们现居弗吉尼亚和马里兰州
living in the Virginia-Maryland area.
太好了
Oh, great.
凭我一人之力没法搜查那么大范围
I can't cover this much ground by myself.
你负责弗吉尼亚  我负责马里兰州
You take Virginia. I'll take Maryland.
就当你非正式地晋升为外勤探员了
Just consider this an unofficial battlefield promotion to field agent.
还有  用这台手机联系我  不要用你的
Also, call me on this, not your regular phone.
我更喜欢躲在幕后操作电脑
I'm more of a behind-the-scenes computer guy.
恰克  我知道我的要求有点过分
Chuck, I know I'm asking a lot,
可是现在我能信任的人少之又少
but there's a short list of people that I trust right now.
其中一个被冤枉入狱了
One of them is in jail for something he didn't do,
另外一个就是你
and the other one is you.
说实话
I got to tell you
他们把你的案子派给我时  我松了口气
I was relieved when they gave me your case
因为我知道这世上能帮你的人
'cause I thought if anybody can help you,
非我莫属
it's gonna be me.
约翰  你永远都扮演不了好警察
John, you could never play the good cop.
直接问吧  别拐弯抹角了
Just ask the questions, and let's get this thing going.
你为什么拒绝请辩护律师
Why'd you waive your right to an attorney?
我没什么要辩护的
I have nothing to defend.
我有罪
I'm guilty.
你在到达监狱前就打算毒死纳萨尔吗
So you intended to poison Nassar before you arrived at the prison?
我用盐包装着铊
I had the Thallium
藏在我的口袋里
in a salt packet hidden in my pocket.
你不担心会被监控录像拍到吗
And you weren't at all concerned about surveillance footage?
北厅的走廊里有个盲点区
There's a blind spot in the North Hall corridor.
数年前一位探员告诉我的
An officer told me about it some years ago
以防我需要私下会会某个犯人
in case I needed to have an off-the-record with a prisoner.
我等摄像头关掉后
I waited until we cleared the cameras.
经过食品托盘
I passed the food tray.
把盐放到了纳萨尔的盘子里
Put the salt in Nassar's plate.
你怎么知道盘子是他的
How'd you know it was his?
他是穆斯林
He's Muslim.
特别为他准备了清真食物
Specially prepared halal meals.
我们能核实他所说的这一切吗
Can we verify everything he's saying?
我的团队正在查  先生  但至今为止
My team's working on it, sir, but so far, everything he said
他的供词符合现场取得的法医证据
matches the forensic evidence taken from the scene.
你跟杰森·阿特伍德是同期吧
You came up with Jason Atwood, right?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
我们在匡提科时同班
We were in the same class at Quantico.
第一次任务是一起做的
Had our first assignments together.
你觉得他
Could you ever imagine
会是犯下这种罪行的人吗
that he was capable of committing such a crime?
我在职业责任办公室十三年了  总统先生
I've worked in the Office of Professional Responsibility for 13 years, Mr. President.
有时候我们也不愿把人往坏处想
We may not want to think the worst of people,
但有时我们别无选择
but sometimes they leave us no choice.
好吧
Right.
先生
Sir.
查到了国安局揭发者的最新消息
We have an update on the NSA whistleblower.
好的
Okay.
-总统先生  -先生
- Mr. President. - Sir.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们找到他了  先生
We found him, sir.
-我们找到加百利·汤普森了  -他在哪里
- We found Gabriel Thompson. - Where is he?
他潜逃了  总统先生
He's on foreign soil, Mr. President.
我以为我们冻结了他的护照
I thought we froze his passport.
-他是怎么逃出去的  -他没有
- How did he get out? - He didn't.
他就在我们旁边
He's right down the street.
抱歉  我不明白
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
他在委内瑞拉大使馆内寻求庇护
He's seeking asylum in the Venezuelan Embassy.
美国与之没有引渡条约  总统先生
No extradition treaty with the U.S., sir.
你跟我说他现在就在华盛顿特区
You're telling me he's right here in Washington, D.C.,
而我们却无计可施
and we can't touch him?
恐怕我们不能把加百利·汤普森转交给贵国
I'm afraid I cannot turn over Gabril Thompson,
总统先生
Mr. President.
他在寻求庇护  我们必须尊重他的要求
He's seeking asylum, and we must respect that.
大使先生  拒不交出一个
Mr. Ambassador, there is a big difference
贩卖毒品的轻罪犯人
between not sending back a petty criminal
和一个对国家安全
who was arrested for marijuana
造成威胁的逃犯之间是有很大区别的
and a fugitive who we consider a threat to our national security.
严格地说不是这样  总统先生
Not technically, Mr. President.
我无法决定贵国法律
I can't dictate your nation's laws,
反之亦然
and you cannot dictate mine.
委内瑞拉方面还不会把他交出来
Venezuela won't give him back...yet.
我来重新制定策略  看有什么结果
I'll circle back to the drawing board, see what I can do.
黑兹尔顿的事情刻不容缓  先生
We're still on the clock with Hazelton, sir.
一件一件来吧  赛斯
One thing at a time, Seth.
一件一件来  什么时候的习惯
One thing at a time? Since when?
麦克利什议员
Congressman MacLeish,
在你第一次去阿富汗执行任务的时候
now, during your first tour in Afghanistan,
你因为英勇作战为被授予青铜星章
you were awarded a Bronze Star for combat bravery.
乔治先生
请你尽可能回忆在2005年11月14日
now, can you please describe the events of November 14, 2005,
发生的事情
to the best of your recollection?
你能尽力地回忆一下2005年11月14日
Can you describe the events of November 14, 2005,
发生了什么吗
to the best of your recollection?
麦克利什队长带领着一队游骑兵特种部队
Captain MacLeish led a Ranger Special Forces unit...
来到了距马尔扎很远的一个阿富汗村庄
...into a remote Afghani village outside of Marja.
我们刚进村就受到了路边炸弹的袭击
As soon as we moved in, our unit hit an IED, and...
我们遭到了塔利班武装力量的伏击
...we were ambushed by Taliban forces.
叛乱分子武装精良
Insurgents were heavily armed, and...
我们瞬间被敌人压制
...we were pinned down almost immediately.
伤亡惨重
Hit, bleeding...
一半人在顽强求生
Half my men clinging to life.
另一半则瑟瑟发抖
The other half frozen in fear.
我属于后半部分的人
And I -- And I include myself in that.
本能使然
I acted on pure instinct.
麦克利什队长独自一人与叛军战斗
Captain MacLeish returned enemy fire single-handedly,
击退了叛乱分子
drove back the insurgents...
让我们及时获得了救治
...allowing medics to get to us in time.
事实上
The truth is
那天由我负责的任务失败了
I presided over a failed mission that day.
我们没有攻下村庄  并且损失惨重
We didn't take the village, and we lost a lot of good men.
我能活下来多亏了麦克利什队长
I'm alive - because of Captain MacLeish.
只有一个词可以描绘他那样的人
So there's only one word to use to describe a man like him.
他是一个英雄
He's a hero.
我的奖章表彰了我的英勇
Well, that's what my medal says I am,
但是说到英雄
but a hero?
很惭愧  我只是做了常人会做的事情
No. I only did what anyone in my position would have done.
我不是一个英雄
It doesn't make me a hero.
只是一个今天各位看到的普通人
It simply makes me who I am today.
每一个他队伍里的人回答都完全一致
Every guy in his platoon says the same thing.
我猜猜  他是一个英雄
Let me guess -- that he's a hero.
我知道  我也得到了同样的回答
I know. Same answer I got, too.
也许你的线人搞错了
Maybe your informant was wrong.
或者也许所有人事先统一了口径
Or maybe everyone got the same talking points.
我还有一个采访要做
I got one interview left.
不到最后我不会放弃的
I'm not giving up till it's over.
你知道你在我的办公室呆的时间比我还长吧
You know you spend a lot more time in my office than I do, right?
我们需要讨论一下黑兹尔顿的事
We need to talk about Hazelton.
不要慌张  这件事会平息的
Don't worry about it. It'll blow over.
-给我一点时间  -不  不会的
- Just give it some time. - No, it won't.
总统不能把我放在第一位
And the president can't put me first,
因为让这个国家复苏的关键立法
not before critical legislation we need
比我更为重要
to get this country back on its feet.
经济刺激法案 创造工作岗位
Stimulus bills, job creation --
这些都需要拨款
Those things go through appropriations,
需要通过黑泽尔顿
through Hazelton.
艾米丽  总统在我泄露艾尔萨卡视频后
Emily, the President didn't accept my resignation
也没有接受我的辞呈
when I leaked the Al-Sakar video.
他当时都不怎么了解我
He barely even knew me.
你是他最信任的顾问
You're his most trusted adviser.
-他不会接受的  我知道  -我知道
- He's not gonna accept yours. - I know.
所以你必须接受
Which is why you're gonna accept it.
不
No.
保护总统是你的职责
It's your job to protect the President,
哪怕是要保护他不要被自己伤害
even when that means protecting him from himself.
艾米丽  你有没有想过
Emily, have you ever considered the fact
他不愿意接受你的辞呈
that he won't accept your resignation
是因为他需要你
because he needs you here?
而且不只是他需要你
And he's not the only one.
我可以等会再来
I can come back.
-不用  -没事
- No, no. - You're fine.
-怎么了  -留下吧
- What is it? - Stay.
我早就提醒过你这种情况了
This is what I like to call "I told you so" --
这是一份全国的媒体名录
a list of every media outlet in the country
以及他们请求对总统进行独家专访
and their requests for an exclusive with the president
想要讨论
to discuss, among other things,
纳萨尔谋杀案调查事宜
the Nassar murder investigation.
直接拒绝他们吧  赛斯
Feel free to tell them no, Seth.
你知道的
You know that.
这也不能怪他们
Can't blame them for trying.
谁不想跟总统聊一聊
I mean, who doesn't want five minutes with the President?
等等  你刚说什么
Wait, what did you just say?
我说谁不想...
I said who doesn't want --
跟总统聊一聊
five minutes with the President.
艾米丽  打给委内瑞拉大使
Emily, call the Venezuelan Ambassador,
告诉我我这就过去
and you tell him I'm on my way.
-刚刚发生了什么  -不知道
- What just happened? - No idea.
太抱歉了
I'm so sorry.
我没有意识到你丈夫已经去世了
I-I didn't realize your husband had passed away.
他瞒着我再服兵役
He re-upped without telling me.
他说不能坐视不管
He said he couldn't leave things the way they were.
他跟突击队的首次出征
And his first tour with the Ranger unit --
是由彼得·麦克利什议员指挥的
that was commanded by Congressman Peter MacLeish.
我想是的
I think so.
史蒂文不爱说他服役时的事
Steven never liked talking about his service.
我甚至没有意识到他很喜欢他的部队生活
I didn't even realize he enjoyed his time in the Army
直到部队把他的储物柜寄回家
until one day the Army shipped home his foot locker.
里面全都是纪念品
In it were all these mementos --
他赢得的奖章
You know, medals that he had won,
他的老战友的信件
letters from his old buddies.
还有一大把服役时的照片
He had tons of pictures of his tours.
莎拉 介意我看看那个储物柜吗
Sarah, do you mind if I take a look at that foot locker?
当然可以
Sure.
就在这边
Right this way.
谢谢
Thanks.
汤普森先生  我是亚伦·肖尔
Mr. Thompson, I'm Aaron Shore,
总统幕僚长
Chief of Staff to the President.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我现在在委内瑞拉国土  肖尔先生
I'm on Venezuelan soil, Mr. Shore.
你不能逮捕我
You can't arrest me.
我很清楚外交法
I'm well aware of diplomatic law.
那你为什么要来这里
Well, then, why are you here?
因为我知道你想要什么
Because I know what you want.
真的吗
Really?
CNN说我想要激进的政府透明公开
CNN says I want radical transparency.
《纽约时报》说我想要无政府状态
The New York Times says I want anarchy.
你又有何猜想呢  肖尔先生
What's your guess, Mr. Shore?
跟总统聊一聊
Five minutes with the President.
你凭什么这么确定我想见总统
What makes you so sure I want to see the President?
你在网上发布的内容非常详细
You've been very specific with what you've posted on the Internet.
首先你攻击了里士满前总统的所有内阁成员
First you attacked members of the Richmond cabinet --
唯独没有攻击柯克曼
every one of them, except Kirkman.
接着你又转向他最信任的顾问
Then you went after his most trusted adviser.
你确保了他注意到你
You made sure he'd notice.
是不是八九不离十了
Am I getting warm?
没错
Yes.
用这方法找自由世界的领袖会面
Hell of a way to get an audience with
还真是费尽周折
the leader of the free world.
我们都只能尽全力  肖尔先生
We use the tools we have, Mr. Shore.
没错  但是你伤害了
Yes, but you've hurt,
也许是永久性地伤害了
perhaps irreparably, a good friend,
总统的一位至交好友也是他忠诚的顾问
a brilliant, loyal adviser to the president,
而你还需要得到我的许可
and being that I'm the one person
才能见到总统
who can grant you access to the president,
为什么我要允许你见总统
why should I reward you with his time?
我不得不把艾米丽·罗迪斯推到风口上
Because I had to hang Emily Rhodes in the wind
来吸引你的注意
to get your attention.
但我同样也能拯救她的职业生涯
But I'm also the guy that can save her career.
他们都参加了那次任务
They were on the same mission.
卡特兰和麦克利什认识彼此
Catalan and MacLeish know each other.
11/14  这才是线人想让我知道的事
11/14 -- That's what my source wanted me to know.
天啊
Oh, my god.
我知道这算不上确凿证据
Yeah, I know it's not a smoking gun,
但这已经比我们一小时前更接近真相了
but it puts us a hell of a lot closer than it did an hour ago.
恰克  我需要进入反恐怖行动联合数据库
Chuck, I'm going to need into the counter-terror joint database.
该用户已被锁定  无法登陆
恰克
Chuck.
-什么  -你还在听吗
- What? - Are you still there?
该用户已被锁定  无法登陆
-在吗  -他们屏蔽了我的电脑
- Hello? - They shut me out of my computer.
-什么  -我的账号登陆不上了
- What? - My login's not working.
法索肯定知道
Foerstel must know
你未经许可就把麦克利什的档案带出来了
that you took MacLeish's files off-site without clearance.
他正在朝我走来
He is heading right towards me.
也就是说他也在找你
That means he's gonna be looking for you, too.
汉娜  不要回来  想办法
Hannah, don't come back. Find a way.
解决这事
Finish this.
加百利·汤普森说想和我见面吗
Gabriel Thompson wants to set a meeting with me?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
在一号楼里他把这个给了我
And to facilitate one, he gave me this.
-是什么  -是他表示诚意的东西  先生
- What is it? - It's a show of good faith, sir.
这里面的东西能够证明艾米丽说的
It's proof that everything Emily said
所有关于黑兹尔顿参议员的事情都是真的
about Senator Hazelton is true --
里面记录了参议员一年内与一位助手的
A year's worth of inappropriate e-mails, text messages,
不雅邮件  短信和聊天记录
chats with a Senate page.
他已经同意停止泄露文件
And he's agreed to stop releasing files
并且交出他所有的东西了吗
and hand over everything he has?
如果你愿意见他的话  是的
If you meet with him, yes.
我不确定邀请一个窃取保密文件的人
I'm not sure inviting a man who stole classified documents
前来白宫是个好的选择
into the White House is an option,
无论他手里有什么
no matter what he has.
但是我们确实需要解决
But we do have to take care of this business
黑兹尔顿参议员这件事
with Senator Hazelton.
看看是不是现在就可以把他带过来
Let's see if we can get him over here now.
-好的  先生  -谢谢  亚伦
- Yes, sir. - Thank you, Aaron.
先生
Sir.
霍斯拉滕议员  上次我们约定过
Congresswoman Hookstraten, last time we spoke,
我会向你持续汇报国会大厦爆炸案的进展
I told you I'd keep you updated on the Capitol bombing.
你在105房间找到你想要的东西了吗
Did you find what you were looking for in room 105?
是的
Yes, I did.
我需要你帮忙拖延麦克利什的听证会
And I need you to delay the MacLeish hearings.
继续说
Go on.
议员  我不能在电话里详说
Congresswoman, I can't talk about this over the phone,
但是我找到了能够
but I'm working a lead
把彼得·麦克利什拉下台的证据
that could prove damning to Peter MacLeish.
但我还需要一些时间
But I need time.
威尔士小姐  你这是要让我用名声做担保
Ms. Wells, you're asking me to put my reputation on the line.
需要多少时间
How much time?
你能给我的全部时间
As much as you can give me.
总统先生
Mr. President.
谢谢你抽出时间
Thank you for taking the time.
我认为我说得已经很明确了
I thought I made myself clear.
她为什么还在这里工作
Why is she still working here?
因为  参议员
Because, Senator,
我才能决定谁在这里工作
I'm the one who chooses which of my staffers I let go.
而我想证明一件事
And I try to make a point
也许会用到不光彩的手段
by not starting out with my best one.
什么
Excuse me?
罗迪斯女士说的所有关于你的事情都是真的
Everything Ms. Rhodes said about you is true,
而我有证据可以证明
and I have the proof to back it up.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
你应该听闻了我们最近和
I think you've heard of our recent interactions
加百利·汤普森的交涉  那个国安局告密者
with Gabriel Thompson, the NSA whistleblower?
目前为止  他的爆料
So far, everything that he's released
全都百分百准确
has proved to be 100% accurate.
先生  他有你的确凿信息
Sir, he has you dead to rights.
一个十八岁的参议员助手
An 18-year-old Senate page.
这是勒索
This is extortion.
不  参议员
No, Senator,
我只是给你看事实
I am simply presenting you with the truth.
勒索是以美国经济稳定
Extortion would be threatening
作为要挟
to compromise the American economic stability
胁迫我开除幕僚的一员
unless I fire one of my staff members
因为她写了你不喜欢的东西
because she wrote something that you didn't like.
你结婚三十五年
You have a wife of 35 years,
是两个好孩子的父亲  三个孩子的祖父
two beautiful children, three grandchildren.
早些时候  你为了陪他们退休了
Earlier, you retired to spend time with them.
我强烈建议你考虑再次退休
I strongly suggest you consider doing that again.
你呢
So, what about you?
你还想再待一会吗
Think you want to stick around a little longer?
幸运的是  我没有别的地方想去了
Luckily, there's no place I'd rather be.
很好
Good.
餐馆
结果发现
So, it turns out
美国最喜爱的副总统人选
that America's favorite vice presidential candidate
和中情局头号通缉的雇佣兵
and the CIA's most wanted mercenary
相互认识
know each other.
-你应该不会相信这是巧合吧  -抱歉
- I guess you're not buying it's a coincidence? - Sorry.
如果卡特兰的确为11/14任务收集情报
If Catalan worked intel on the 11/14 mission,
中情局应该会留有档案
the CIA would have a file on it.
你去调档案了吗
Did you pull it?
如果有的话我会的
I would have if there was one.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?
-有人销毁了  -所以我更深入地调查了
- Someone buried it? - So I looked deeper.
我找到了这个
I found this.
是由战地中情局联络员写的
It was written by an Agency liaison on the ground.
跟麦克利什说的不太一样
Not quite the same story that MacLeish has been telling.
"2005年11月14日
"On November 14, 2005,
在其队员被塔利班狙击手射杀后
a Ranger unit massacred a series of Afghani villages
一支突击小队血洗了数个阿富汗村庄
after several of their unit had been killed by a Taliban sniper.
24小时内屠杀3座村庄  死伤无数”
3 villages in 24 hours. Countless dead."
五角大楼洗白了这件事吗
And the Pentagon whitewashed this?
彼得·麦克利什不是什么战争英雄
Peter MacLeish isn't a war hero.
不  他是战争犯
No, he's a war criminal.
我听说了艾米丽的事
I heard about Emily.
算是解决了那个危机
So that's one crisis resolved.
我在看另一个
Now I'm reading about the other one --
加百利·汤普森
Gabriel Thompson.
这是他的心理档案
This is his psychological profile
由国务院
courtesy of the State Department,
联邦执法部门和国安局提供的
federal law enforcement, and the NSA.
艾丽克斯  我到底漏了什么
Alex, what the hell am I missing?
好像每次我转过头
I mean, it seems like every time I turn around,
就发现有人忠心耿耿地服务国家
there's someone who's served this country faithfully,
然后突然就打算背弃国家
and then out of the blue, decides to turn against it.
你是在说告密者
Are you talking about the whistleblower
还是杰森·亚特伍德
or Jason Atwood now?
两者都是
Both of them.
国安局分析员变成了叛徒
NSA analyst turns traitor.
联调局副局长杀了人
Deputy FBI director commits murder.
说不通
It doesn't add up.
你凭直觉怎么看汤普森
What does your gut say about Thompson?
撇开我的国家安全团队的看法
Well, despite the advice of my National Security Team,
总统办公厅的批文
the protocols of the Office of the Presidency,
和我自己的常识
and my own common sense...
我觉得这家伙没有疯
...I don't think this guy's crazy.
他很聪明
He's smart.
他知道一旦他离开了大使馆的保护
And he knows once he leaves the protection of the embassy,
他免不了长久的牢狱之灾
he's going to prison for a long time.
所以他想和你面谈的原因
So whatever the reason for wanting to sit down with you is,
一定重要到让他不惜舍弃性命
it must be pretty important for him to trade in his life for it.
会是什么呢
Well, what could it be?
这就是我想不通的部分了
That's the part I can't figure out.
你会想通的  只要调查得再深入一些
You will. Just need to look deeper.
清空你的口袋
Empty your pockets.
过一会儿
In a few moments,
他们就会押送你去联邦监狱
they're going to be taking you to federal prison,
所以我长话短说
so I need to make this quick.
我知道你有一个继女叫夏洛特
I know you had a stepdaughter named Charlotte
她是埃尔斯沃思议员办公室的实习生
who was an intern in Congressman Ellsworth's office.
我知道她参加了国情咨文演讲
I know that she was at the State of the Union
结果在爆炸中丧生
and died in the bombing.
不同的生父  不同的姓氏
Different birth father, different last name
让人难以把这一系列事串起来
made it harder to make the connection.
我也知道你把她从襁褓里抚养成人
I also understand that you raised her since she was a baby,
所以她也是你的孩子
so she was yours, too.
绝不该有白发人送黑发人
Children should never die before their parents.
是的  不应该
No. No, they should not.
我对你的遭遇深表遗憾
And I am very sorry for your loss.
-谢谢你  总统先生
- Thank you, Mr. President.
作为一个父亲
And as a father,
我理解你的愤怒和悲伤
I understand your anger and your grief.
但这仍然不能回答我的关键问题
But it still doesn't answer my main question.
你牺牲了这么多就为了与我见上这一面
You sacrificed a great deal to have this meeting with me.
为什么
Why?
我需要一个我能信任的人
I needed someone I could trust
以确保这样的攻击不会再发生
to make sure an attack like that never happens again.
是什么让你认为你可以信任我
And what makes you think you can trust me?
我做了研究
Oh, I did my research,
读了你发的每一封邮件  写的每一份文件
read every e-mail you sent, every document you wrote.
你的道德观无可挑剔
Your ethics are above reproach.
更不用说每四条短信就有一条是发给孩子的
Not to mention every fourth text you send is to your children.
那个证物袋里是我的零钱
Inside that evidence bag is my pocket change.
里面有一个假的25美分硬币
There is a fake coin, a quarter.
那其中是我偷走的硬盘
Inside it is the hard drive I took.
我没有做任何备份
I did not make copies.
你为什么把这个给我
Why are you giving this to me?
因为你有比我更大的麻烦
Because you have much bigger problems than me,
总统先生
Mr. President.
交接车辆已经备好
Transport is ready.
别随意把文件12-80C给别人看  长官
Careful who you show file 12-80C to, sir.
迈克  那个人放弃了他的事业和自由
Mike, that man gave up his career and his freedom
就为了那个硬盘上的东西
for what's on this hard drive.
我要知道背后的原因
I want to know why.
这个笔记本是物理隔离的
This laptop's air-gapped.
所以如果这个硬盘上有恶意软件
So if there's malware on this drive,
只有这一台计算机会被感染
it'll only affect this computer.
解码软件已经在运行中了
De-encryption software's already running.
你是怎么知道这些的
How do you know all this?
在我被分配给你做保镖前
Before I was assigned to your protective detail,
我辗转于各种调查工作
I rotated through investigations,
威胁评估  还有我们的技术部门
threat assessment, and our technical department.
在计算机编程方面干了两年半
2 1/2 years staring at computer code.
我只想说  我更喜欢给你工作
Let's just say I like working for you more.
好的
Good.
听着  在我们清楚这上面到底有什么之前
Look, until we know exactly what this is,
不要告诉别人这件事  明白吗
I want it to stay between us. Understood?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
总统先生
Mr. President.
霍斯拉滕议员刚刚打来电话要求延期
Congresswoman Hookstraten just called for an extended recess.
她要推迟麦克利什的听证会
She's delaying MacLeish's hearing.
为什么
Why?
她很狡猾不肯说  但是有个众议院的人说
She's being cagey, but a House staffer says
她有关于麦克利什的信息
she's got information on MacLeish
可能会对听证会影响很大
that could be critical to the hearing.
我们正努力获取更多信息
We're trying to find out more.
女议员和我常常意见相左
The Congresswoman and I don't agree on much,
但她不是疯子
but she's not crazy.
她一定认为她手里他的重要信息
She must think that she's got something substantial on him,
否则她不会冒这个风险
otherwise she wouldn't risk it.
-把麦克利什叫来  -是的  长官
- Get me MacLeish. - Yes, sir.
迈克  我会确保你不被打扰
Mike, I'll make sure you're not disturbed.
我就不妨开门见山了
Well, I guess I'll just get right to it.
霍斯拉滕议员认为她有你的把柄
Congresswoman Hookstraten thinks she has information on you
能够左右听证会
that can alter the hearings.
你知道是什么吗
You know what it is?
不  我不知道
No. No, I don't.
但如果你有事情想要告诉我  彼得
But if there's something you need to tell me, Peter,
请现在就说
this is the time.
我之前告诉你的一切都是真的
Well, everything I've ever told you has been true,
我对我的祖国忠心耿耿
I served my country loyally,
我全身心投入到我的家庭
I dedicated myself to my family,
我选区的人民  和整个国家中去
the people of my district, the entire nation.
好吧
Okay,
我希望你能理解我必须得问问
okay, I hope you understand I had to ask.
当然
Yeah, of course, of course,
我也很感谢你的支持
and thank you for your support,
你知道  这对我来说真的很重要
you know it always -- it always means the world.
抱歉麻烦你了  彼得
Sorry to trouble you, Peter.
别这么说
No, no.
我告辞了
Okay.
其实  长官
No, you know, sir, there --
有一件事一直困扰着我
there's something that's been nagging at me.
杰森·阿特伍德供认谋杀了马吉德·纳萨尔
Jason Atwood confessed to murdering Majid Nassar,
他最器重的
the agent he valued the most --
汉娜·威尔士特别探员
Special Agent Hannah Wells --
或许我弄错了
I don't know,
我听说她在爆炸中失去了一个人
I-I heard she lost someone in the bombing,
或许这之间有什么联系
maybe that's got something to do with it, but...
她的注意力总是在我身上
She seemed to be a bit obsessed with me,
我只是希望她不会试着用阴谋论
I just hope she isn't trying to convince the speaker
来说服议长
of any, uh, fantasy or conspiracy theory.
谢谢你告诉我
Thank you for letting me know,
我会注意的
I'll keep an eye out.
好的
Yeah.
晚安  彼得
Good night, Peter.
众议院
时候刚好  威尔士探员
Agent Wells, just in time.
我找到了关于彼得·麦克利什的证据
I found the evidence I was looking for on Peter MacLeish,
我在去议会的路上
I'll explain everything when I get there,
我到了后会解释一切的
I'm just heading up Constitution now.
谢谢你告诉我
Thank you for letting me know.
乔治议员
Congressman George,
让委员会集合
gather the rest of the committee,
我的证人还有10分钟就到
my witness will be here in 10 minutes.
好的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我之前没有机会谢谢你
I didn't get a chance to thank you earlier
保住了我的工作
for saving my job today,
谢谢你
thank you.
举手之劳
Don't even mention it,
你是个好员工
you're a good employee.
你做这么多只为了留住个好员工
You did all of that to keep a good employee around.
好吧  或许我有其他的理由
All right, I may have other reasons.
我还有工作要做
Well, I have work to do,
如果你想起了那些理由  记得告诉我
if you think of any of those reasons, let me know, okay?
艾米丽
Hey, Emily,
你今晚完成工作后
when you're finished with work tonight...
一起吃个晚饭
Dinner?
好的
Okay.
快点啊
Come on!
我找到了12-80C文件
I located File 12-80C,
我在等你一起打开看
I was waiting for you before I opened it.
让开
Move!
这是谁创建的
Who created this?
是我们  长官
We did, sir,
美国政府创建的
United States Government,
2013年11月17号创建
November 17, 2013.
威胁评估特别委员会  五角大楼 顶级加密
威胁评估特别委员会  五角大楼
Special Committee for Threat Assessment, Pentagon,
顶级加密
Classified Top Secret.
这是国会爆炸
This is the Capitol bombing,
一模一样的模式
right down to the same ordinance,
他们在评估安全漏洞
they're assessing our security vulnerabilities,
他们在爆炸发生数年前就演习过
they war-gamed this out years before it even happened.
政府中有人把
Someone inside the U.S. Government
蓝图交给了马吉德·纳萨尔
handed over the blueprints to Majid Nassar
导致了国会被炸
for the Capitol bombing.
我们中间出了个叛徒
There's a traitor among us.
■
扫描二维码
关注凤凰八卦